[
  {
    "id": 1,
    "question": "What powerful object does the Fellowship of the Ring set out to destroy?",
    "options": [
      "The One Ring",
      "The Elven Dagger",
      "The Mithril Shield",
      "The Arkenstone"
    ],
    "correct_option": "The One Ring"
  },
  {
    "id": 2,
    "question": "Who is the primary antagonist in 'The Lord of the Rings' trilogy?",
    "options": [
      "Saruman",
      "Sauron",
      "Gollum",
      "Saruman"
    ],
    "correct_option": "Sauron"
  },
  {
    "id": 3,
    "question": "What race is Legolas, one of the members of the Fellowship?",
    "options": [
      "Dwarf",
      "Elf",
      "Human",
      "Hobbit"
    ],
    "correct_option": "Elf"
  },
  {
    "id": 4,
    "question": "In which fictional world does 'The Lord of the Rings' take place?",
    "options": [
      "Middle-earth",
      "Narnia",
      "Westeros",
      "Hogwarts"
    ],
    "correct_option": "Middle-earth"
  },
  {
    "id": 5,
    "question": "What is the name of Gandalf's sword?",
    "options": [
      "Sting",
      "Glamdring",
      "Andúril",
      "Narsil"
    ],
    "correct_option": "Glamdring"
  },
  {
    "id": 6,
    "question": "Who is the author of 'The Lord of the Rings' book series?",
    "options": [
      "J.K. Rowling",
      "George R.R. Martin",
      "J.R.R. Tolkien",
      "C.S. Lewis"
    ],
    "correct_option": "J.R.R. Tolkien"
  },
  {
    "id": 7,
    "question": "Which character becomes corrupted by the One Ring?",
    "options": [
      "Frodo Baggins",
      "Aragorn",
      "Boromir",
      "Legolas"
    ],
    "correct_option": "Boromir"
  },
  {
    "id": 8,
    "question": "What is the capital city of Gondor?",
    "options": [
      "Rivendell",
      "Minas Tirith",
      "Helm's Deep",
      "Isengard"
    ],
    "correct_option": "Minas Tirith"
  },
  {
    "id": 9,
    "question": "What is the name of the creature that Frodo and Sam encounter in the Dead Marshes?",
    "options": [
      "Shelob",
      "Balrog",
      "Gollum",
      "Nazgûl"
    ],
    "correct_option": "Shelob"
  },
  {
    "id": 10,
    "question": "Which actor played the role of Frodo Baggins in the film trilogy?",
    "options": [
      "Elijah Wood",
      "Viggo Mortensen",
      "Ian McKellen",
      "Orlando Bloom"
    ],
    "correct_option": "Elijah Wood"
  },
  {
    "id": 11,
    "question": "What is the name of the hobbit who becomes the Ring-bearer?",
    "options": [
      "Samwise Gamgee",
      "Merry Brandybuck",
      "Frodo Baggins",
      "Pippin Took"
    ],
    "correct_option": "Frodo Baggins"
  },
  {
    "id": 12,
    "question": "Which creature guides Frodo and Sam through the treacherous paths of Mordor?",
    "options": [
      "Gollum",
      "Gimli",
      "Treebeard",
      "Radagast"
    ],
    "correct_option": "Gollum"
  },
  {
    "id": 13,
    "question": "What is the name of the ancient tree-like beings in Fangorn Forest?",
    "options": [
      "Ents",
      "Hobbits",
      "Orcs",
      "Uruk-hai"
    ],
    "correct_option": "Ents"
  },
  {
    "id": 14,
    "question": "Which member of the Fellowship is known for his skill with a bow and arrow?",
    "options": [
      "Aragorn",
      "Gimli",
      "Legolas",
      "Boromir"
    ],
    "correct_option": "Legolas"
  },
  {
    "id": 15,
    "question": "What is the name of the inn in Bree where Frodo and his companions meet Aragorn?",
    "options": [
      "The Prancing Pony",
      "The Green Dragon",
      "The Shire's Rest",
      "The Ivy Inn"
    ],
    "correct_option": "The Prancing Pony"
  },
  {
    "id": 16,
    "question": "Which river do Frodo and Sam cross with Gollum's help to enter Mordor?",
    "options": [
      "Morgulduin",
      "Brandywine",
      "Isen",
      "Entwash"
    ],
    "correct_option": "Morgulduin"
  },
  {
    "id": 17,
    "question": "What is the name of the ancient language written on the One Ring?",
    "options": [
      "Elvish",
      "Dwarvish",
      "Black Speech",
      "Entish"
    ],
    "correct_option": "Black Speech"
  },
  {
    "id": 18,
    "question": "Who is the ruler of Rohan during the events of 'The Two Towers'?",
    "options": [
      "Théoden",
      "Éomer",
      "Éowyn",
      "Grima Wormtongue"
    ],
    "correct_option": "Théoden"
  },
  {
    "id": 19,
    "question": "What is the name of the wizard who leads the Fellowship and later becomes Gandalf the White?",
    "options": [
      "Saruman",
      "Radagast",
      "Gandalf the Grey",
      "Alatar"
    ],
    "correct_option": "Gandalf the Grey"
  },
  {
    "id": 20,
    "question": "Which character famously says, 'You shall not pass!' during a confrontation in Moria?",
    "options": [
      "Aragorn",
      "Legolas",
      "Gimli",
      "Gandalf"
    ],
    "correct_option": "Gandalf"
  },
  {
    "id": 21,
    "question": "What is the name of Frodo's uncle, who initially possesses the One Ring?",
    "options": [
      "Bilbo Baggins",
      "Drogo Baggins",
      "Balbo Baggins",
      "Fosco Baggins"
    ],
    "correct_option": "Bilbo Baggins"
  },
  {
    "id": 22,
    "question": "Which ancient artifact is crucial to the defeat of Sauron and the destruction of the One Ring?",
    "options": [
      "The Silmarils",
      "The Palantír",
      "Mount Doom",
      "The Arkenstone"
    ],
    "correct_option": "Mount Doom"
  },
  {
    "id": 23,
    "question": "Who is the leader of the Rangers of the North and goes by the alias 'Strider'?",
    "options": [
      "Elrond",
      "Thranduil",
      "Aragorn",
      "Boromir"
    ],
    "correct_option": "Aragorn"
  },
  {
    "id": 24,
    "question": "What is the name of the spider-like creature encountered by Frodo and Sam in Mordor?",
    "options": [
      "Shelob",
      "Ungoliant",
      "Arachne",
      "Lobelia"
    ],
    "correct_option": "Shelob"
  },
  {
    "id": 25,
    "question": "Which member of the Fellowship is skilled in mining and has a deep affinity for precious stones?",
    "options": [
      "Gimli",
      "Legolas",
      "Boromir",
      "Faramir"
    ],
    "correct_option": "Gimli"
  },
  {
    "id": 26,
    "question": "What is the name of the river that flows through Lothlórien, where the Fellowship meets Galadriel?",
    "options": [
      "Anduin",
      "Celebrant",
      "Lhûn",
      "Erui"
    ],
    "correct_option": "Celebrant"
  },
  {
    "id": 27,
    "question": "Which character is known for his love of pipe-weed, a type of tobacco in Middle-earth?",
    "options": [
      "Gollum",
      "Gandalf",
      "Merry",
      "Pippin"
    ],
    "correct_option": "Gandalf"
  },
  {
    "id": 28,
    "question": "What is the name of the enchanted forest through which the Hobbits travel to reach Tom Bombadil?",
    "options": [
      "Fangorn Forest",
      "Old Forest",
      "Mirkwood",
      "Lothlórien"
    ],
    "correct_option": "Old Forest"
  },
  {
    "id": 29,
    "question": "Who is the steward of Gondor, the father of Boromir and Faramir?",
    "options": [
      "Denethor",
      "Boromir",
      "Faramir",
      "Aragorn"
    ],
    "correct_option": "Denethor"
  },
  {
    "id": 30,
    "question": "What mythical creatures come to the rescue of the Fellowship, carrying them across the mountains after their escape from the mines of Moria?",
    "options": [
      "Eagles",
      "Ents",
      "Dragons",
      "Gwaihir"
    ],
    "correct_option": "Eagles"
  },
  {
    "id": 31,
    "question": "What is the name of the ancient city that Aragorn, Legolas, and Gimli seek refuge in 'The Two Towers'?",
    "options": [
      "Rohan",
      "Gondor",
      "Rivendell",
      "Helm's Deep"
    ],
    "correct_option": "Helm's Deep"
  },
  {
    "id": 32,
    "question": "Who is the master smith who reforges the shards of Narsil into the sword Andúril?",
    "options": [
      "Elrond",
      "Thranduil",
      "Gimli",
      "Celeborn"
    ],
    "correct_option": "Elrond"
  },
  {
    "id": 33,
    "question": "What is the name of the forest where the Ents reside?",
    "options": [
      "Lothlórien",
      "Fangorn",
      "Mirkwood",
      "Old Forest"
    ],
    "correct_option": "Fangorn"
  },
  {
    "id": 34,
    "question": "Which two characters share a deep friendship, often referring to each other as 'my friend'?",
    "options": [
      "Legolas and Gimli",
      "Frodo and Sam",
      "Aragorn and Boromir",
      "Gandalf and Saruman"
    ],
    "correct_option": "Legolas and Gimli"
  },
  {
    "id": 35,
    "question": "What is the name of the creature that carries Frodo and Sam into Mordor?",
    "options": [
      "Eagles",
      "Giant Eagles",
      "Nazgûl",
      "Oliphaunts"
    ],
    "correct_option": "Giant Eagles"
  },
  {
    "id": 36,
    "question": "What power does the One Ring grant its bearer?",
    "options": [
      "Invisibility",
      "Telekinesis",
      "Shape-shifting",
      "Mind control"
    ],
    "correct_option": "Invisibility"
  },
  {
    "id": 37,
    "question": "Which member of the Fellowship is a skilled healer and tends to Frodo's wounds in Rivendell?",
    "options": [
      "Aragorn",
      "Gandalf",
      "Frodo",
      "Elrond"
    ],
    "correct_option": "Aragorn"
  },
  {
    "id": 38,
    "question": "What is the name of the region where the hobbits encounter the Barrow-wights?",
    "options": [
      "The Shire",
      "The Barrow-downs",
      "Bree-land",
      "The Lone-lands"
    ],
    "correct_option": "The Barrow-downs"
  },
  {
    "id": 39,
    "question": "Which character is known for his love of boats and sailing?",
    "options": [
      "Aragorn",
      "Legolas",
      "Frodo",
      "Boromir"
    ],
    "correct_option": "Legolas"
  },
  {
    "id": 40,
    "question": "What is the name of the ancient tree in Fangorn Forest that speaks to Merry and Pippin?",
    "options": [
      "Treebeard",
      "Quickbeam",
      "Old Man Willow",
      "Tom Bombadil"
    ],
    "correct_option": "Treebeard"
  },
  {
    "id": 41,
    "question": "What is the name of the horse given to Legolas by Éomer in 'The Two Towers'?",
    "options": [
      "Shadowfax",
      "Bill the Pony",
      "Arod",
      "Brego"
    ],
    "correct_option": "Arod"
  },
  {
    "id": 42,
    "question": "Which member of the Fellowship is known for his love of second breakfasts?",
    "options": [
      "Frodo",
      "Pippin",
      "Merry",
      "Sam"
    ],
    "correct_option": "Pippin"
  },
  {
    "id": 43,
    "question": "What creature does Frodo encounter in the Dead Marshes that tries to lure him into the water?",
    "options": [
      "Gollum",
      "The Watcher in the Water",
      "Nazgûl",
      "Barrow-wight"
    ],
    "correct_option": "Gollum"
  },
  {
    "id": 44,
    "question": "What is the name of the fortress where Sauron resides and the Eye of Sauron watches over Middle-earth?",
    "options": [
      "Barad-dûr",
      "Orthanc",
      "Minas Morgul",
      "Cirith Ungol"
    ],
    "correct_option": "Barad-dûr"
  },
  {
    "id": 45,
    "question": "Which character is known for his love of gardening and is the head of the gardening community in the Shire?",
    "options": [
      "Samwise Gamgee",
      "Frodo Baggins",
      "Meriadoc Brandybuck",
      "Gandalf"
    ],
    "correct_option": "Samwise Gamgee"
  },
  {
    "id": 46,
    "question": "What is the name of the ancient elf who gives Frodo the light of Eärendil (phial of Galadriel) for protection?",
    "options": [
      "Galadriel",
      "Arwen",
      "Elrond",
      "Glorfindel"
    ],
    "correct_option": "Galadriel"
  },
  {
    "id": 47,
    "question": "What is the nickname of the horse that belonged to Boromir?",
    "options": [
      "Shadowfax",
      "Brego",
      "Arod",
      "Firefoot"
    ],
    "correct_option": "Firefoot"
  },
  {
    "id": 48,
    "question": "In 'The Fellowship of the Ring,' what is the name of the ancient elven song that tells the history of the One Ring?",
    "options": [
      "Lament for Boromir",
      "The Lay of Leithian",
      "The Song of Durin",
      "A Elbereth Gilthoniel"
    ],
    "correct_option": "A Elbereth Gilthoniel"
  },
  {
    "id": 49,
    "question": "What is the name of Frodo's sword that he receives from Bilbo, also known as Sting?",
    "options": [
      "Andúril",
      "Glamdring",
      "Orcrist",
      "Sting"
    ],
    "correct_option": "Sting"
  },
  {
    "id": 50,
    "question": "Who is the king of the Dead Men of Dunharrow, bound by an oath to Isildur?",
    "options": [
      "Théoden",
      "Gimli",
      "Aragorn",
      "Elrond"
    ],
    "correct_option": "Aragorn"
  }
]
